Yori, considering your Japanese roots, are there any Japanese dishes you'd recommend?
Oh, absolutely. Sushi, sashimi, sukiyaki, Japanese barbecue, and for everyday meals,
I love a simple bowl of rice mixed with a raw egg.
You need to be careful in the United States.
Supermarket raw eggs and fish don't quite cut it for making authentic sashimi.
No worries. I usually stick to dining at reputable restaurants.
But even the most reputable establishments can sometimes slip up.
In Japan, you'll find that people are constantly getting infected by parasites.
Despite the common practice of eating sashimi in their culture, the Japanese are not immune to fish parasites.
In coastal regions of Japan, the most advanced medical departments are those treating parasites.
Today, I'll delve into a culinary tale from Japan.
A story of a dish that, due to a singular incident, faced nationwide prohibition.
The story begins with a dish called something like basashi in Japanese.
It is the beef liver sashimi.
Imagine thinly sliced beef liver, delicately seasoned with sesame seeds, green onions, a pinch of salt,
a dash of pepper, and a drizzle of sesame oil, all savored raw.
Its surprisingly gentle and sweet taste, combined with a texture that's both tender and bouncy,
makes it an unforgettable delicacy.
This was a dish I, along with countless others in Japan, would not miss ordering it.
However, following an incident a decade ago, it vanished from Japanese menus.
It was on April 22, 2011, in Toyama Prefecture, Japan.
A man named Kubo rushes home from work to celebrate his son's 14th birthday.
Craving barbecue, the family heads to their neighborhood's affordable grill spot, Yakiniku Ebisu.
Known for their budget-friendly prices, thanks to bulk purchasing that keeps costs low,
this eatery offers dishes like pork neck, belly, chicken skin,
and even the most expensive Wagyu beef for roughly 100 yen to 380 yen.
They are approximately 66 cents to three bucks in U.S. dollars.
Their guarantee to customers is, your satisfaction is on us.
It was this reputation for value and quality that had landed them features on numerous Japanese TV food shows,
and why Kubo's son had his heart set on celebrating there.
Among their orders of various grilled meats, Kubo and his sons each indulged in a 280-yen beef tartare.
Raw beef threads mixed with a custom sauce and an egg yolk, yielding a creamy, rich flavor.
That night, they left satiated and happy.
But joy turned to concern when, the next afternoon, Kubo's son began experiencing severe stomach pain, diarrhea, and vomiting.
Initially attributing it to a minor ailment, the situation rapidly worsened,
leading to a hospital visit where they were diagnosed with an E. coli infection,
a strain deadly enough to cause severe symptoms and even acute kidney failure.
This bacterium's insidious nature lies in its potency.
A mere 10 to 100 bacteria can cause infection, showcasing its alarming infectiousness.
The Kubo family's shared meal, not mindful of using separate serving utensils, allowed the bacteria to spread.
Six days post-dinner, the youngest Kubo was admitted to the ICU with hemolytic uremic syndrome,
unfortunately passing away six months later.
The outbreak ultimately affected 181 individuals, with five tragic fatalities.