Is there no other way to explore the existence of the soul besides weighing it?
Good question.
The year is 1997 and a biology professor from the St. Petersburg State Technical University
in Russia named Konstantin Korotkov wanted to photograph the soul.
How did he come up with such an idea?
It all began in the 1970s when the young Korotkov met an elderly electrical engineer.
Initially he didn't pay much attention until one day he was invited by the KGB.
The KGB wanted to know if any peculiar Europeans had been studying the elderly engineer's
work, cautioning Korotkov to beware of ulterior motives and prevent foreign spies from stealing
the National Treasure Engineer's technology.
This engineer was Semyon Davidovich Kirlian, who, in 1937, was repairing an electrotherapy
device when he noticed sparks of electrical discharge between his hand and the glass-covered
electrode.
Curious, he sought to capture this phenomenon on film.
After countless attempts, Kirlian discovered a method, later known as Kirlian photography.
His photographs gradually gained popularity in Western Europe, where people believed the
material halos shown in the pictures were proof of a universal spirit, validating the
existence of a soul field.
Thus, audacious Westerners sneaked into St Petersburg to interview Kirlian.
After learning the whole story, Korotkov thought it better to learn the technique himself rather
than let others do so.
He visited Kirlian's home to learn the method and found the principle surprisingly simple,
later improving upon the photographic technique.
Korotkov then created a series of scientific equipment and, with everything ready, invited
a photojournalist to witness the soul's photography.
He placed the patient on a glass device connected to an electrode and, at the moment of the
patient's death, took numerous continuous exposure shots.
Eventually, he selected the most representative two photos for comparison.
A bluish phantom halo appeared on the deceased, which Korotkov believed represented the soul
gradually leaving the body.
While Korotkov's experiment seemed fascinating, many doubted its validity.
Korotkov theorized the reduction of the bluish halo might be due to the massive die-off of
cells, slowly losing moisture and heat, though this alone couldn't definitively prove the
soul's existence.
He suggested more persuasive experimental data and a method to capture every moment
of the soul's departure were needed to conclusively prove the soul's presence.
Most netizens believed Korotkov's initial experiments didn't necessarily indicate failure,
merely that the equipment couldn't achieve the desired results.
Despite the experiment feeling inconclusive, the idea of photographing the soul became
quite popular worldwide.
In Detroit, USA, a soul photography studio was opened, claiming every photographed customer
would exhibit a unique soul halo in color and size, reportedly doing good business.
Within a year, three more branches were opened in Seattle, attracting many curious customers.
Some were so fascinated, they wished to start their own soul photography studios.
On June 20, 2001, the University of Houston invited a British doctor to present a similar
experiment on souls.
His report sparked a significant increase in believers of the soul's existence.
Pania, originally a specialist in the field of cardiac arrest and resuscitation, had saved
many patients on the brink of death.
After resuscitation, many described a peculiar sensation to Pania, seemingly observing themselves
lying on the bed.