Hello, I'm Dr. K. Today we are diving into AI and human life speed.
You've probably noticed that the AI revolution is speeding up.
Like generative AI can turn your imagination into images or videos.
I would say this is a real game changer for movies and game creators.
Even in terms of computer programming.
I mean, it can whip up a website for you within 10 to 20 minutes.
Imagine that 30 years back, if you want to build a website like Amazon, you need a team of top engineers.
Now, even a noob can get AI to help him implement it.
As an expert in this field, I would say this is really revolutionary.
But there's a catch.
These AI tools often have an input limit or time limit.
Like Microsoft's Bing, it capsules away 2,000 to 4,000 words.
When it's answering a question, it feels like it's counting each word.
And the new Solar project by OpenAI can only generate 1 to 2 minute videos.
Good point. It seems like these mega companies are just gouting their computational power.
Or they're intentionally adding a lifespan to these AI programs.
Yuri, have you ever wondered about why human beings have lifespans?
First up, telomeres.
Our DNAs like coding or text in a book.
DNAs pretty much set up everything for us.
Your looks, your smartness, you name it.
Imagine your body's information is a huge library.
And those 46 chromosomes in each cell of your body, they're just like 46 books.
The contents in these books shape us.
Telomeres are just like borrow cards on the pocket of the cover.
Where every time the cell copies itself, a line on the borrow card will be gone.
When the card is used up, no more borrowing, no more renew.
It means the cell cannot split anymore.
It means those cells have reached their lifespans.
Research says telomere lengths can predict lifespan pretty well.
For example, women's telomere lengths are longer than men's.
Hence, women generally outlive men.
In the U.S., women live about five to six years longer than men.