Pania named this phenomenon near-death experience, where patients vividly saw their souls floating
out of their bodies, a bright white light in front of them, and could observe their
own limbs hovering about 20 centimetres from the ceiling, witnessing doctors busily trying
to save their bodies through walls and their anxious relatives waiting outside.
In the future, if I get a chance, I will explain more about on near-death experience to you.
Pania reasoned, if a patient's soul could float after death, then placing a whiteboard
on the ceiling with unseen words written on it could test the theory.
If the soul floated up, it would see the words, assuming these words remain unseen by the
patient before and after resuscitation.
Pania conducted experiments with over a hundred patients.
Later, seven resuscitated patients correctly identified the words written on the whiteboard,
an astonishing outcome.
Pania's report seemed to prove the existence of the soul, yet it could only go so far.
Scientific experiments require proof, repeatability, and verification.
Decades passed, and aside from Pania, no one else has achieved such critical results, making
Pania's findings a singular piece of evidence and insufficient to prove the soul's existence.
We've discussed soul weighing, soul photography, and out-of-body experiences, none of which
sound particularly compelling or scientifically grounded.
The most compelling explanation for the soul's existence comes from Sir Roger Penrose, a
Nobel Prize-winning physicist.
Penrose suggests the human brain isn't like traditional computers that rely on bit-by-bit
computation.
It resembles a quantum computer, using qubits to allow both zero and one to be computed
simultaneously.
He gave a typical example.
When thinking about what to eat, whether apples, fried chicken, or fries, one doesn't sequentially
consider fried chicken, then apples and fries, but thinks about them all at once.
In this state, the qubits are entangled, like Schrödinger's cat, which exists in a state
of life and death until observed.
Similarly, when the brain decides what to eat, the wave function collapses, and a decision
is made instantly.
However, Penrose has yet to find traces of quantum computing in brain tissue.
In the 1990s, Stuart Hameroff, the director of the Center for Consciousness Studies at
the University of Arizona, read Penrose's The Emperor's New Mind and realized a magical
structure exists in the human brain.
Microtubules, filamentous structures that help form the skeleton of neurons and other
cells, may allow electrons to exist simultaneously in the universe and the brain, suggesting
our soul is half in the brain and half somewhere deep in the universe, entangled regardless
of distance.
Penrose and Hameroff called this orchestrated objective reduction theory.
According to their research, quantum is immortal, meaning even after death, the entangled quantum
remains, akin to the traditional notion of ghosts.
Mainstream science harshly criticized the theory upon its introduction, with no one
knowing if microtubule electrons could achieve quantum superposition or equipment to prove
it.
Moreover, neuroscientists note the cerebellum, filled with neurons and microtubules, doesn't
affect consciousness even when severely damaged.
It's unlikely the soul resides only in the brain and not the cerebellum.
Many believe Penrose's research veered off course, but the Nobel Committee showed more
tolerance and rationality.
Regardless of Penrose's controversial views, his contribution to science cannot be erased.