E. coli is a name familiar to many, yet there are various strains of E. coli.
Most strains of E. coli are harmless to humans.
However, the strain that infected the Kubo family, the hemorrhagic E. coli, is deadly.
It can cause severe abdominal pain, diarrhoea, fever, and vomiting, and it may lead to hemolytic
uremic syndrome.
Once the E. coli reaches the colon, immune cells begin to attack.
When these hemorrhagic E. coli bacteria are destroyed, they release a large amount of
toxins.
These toxins enter the bloodstream, attacking red blood cells and platelets while circulating
throughout the body.
If the toxins are not quickly expelled, they can cause acute brain inflammation and acute
renal failure.
This explains why the entire Kubo family was infected, but the youngest son had the most
severe symptoms.
Because he took antidiarrheal medication early in the complication, the accumulated toxins
could not be expelled from the body, worsening his condition.
This incident cast a spotlight on Yakiniku Ebisu, revealing laxes in their hygiene practices
and handling of raw ingredients.
Amid public outcry and legal battles, the restaurant's management faced bankruptcy,
dodging compensation responsibilities.
The subsequent legal ruling mandated a substantial payout to the victims but absolved the president
of criminal liability, citing a lack of awareness about the risks of E. coli at the time.
As the number of infections rose, the finger of blame pointed squarely at Yakiniku Ebisu,
the barbecue restaurant.
Netizens dug up footage from a previous TV interview showing staff wiping dishes with
a cloth used for bathing and mixing meat with their bare hands.
The video's release sparked a wave of angry emails directed at Ebisu.
Facing public outrage, Ebisu's president held a press conference on May 2nd.
Beyond apologizing, the president revealed more industry secrets not known to the public.
What did this mean?
E. coli, as the name suggests, resides in the colon.
Thus, slaughterhouses process beef and offal separately to prevent bacteria from the innards
contaminating the meat.
However, that's not enough because the meat's surface is most prone to bacterial infection.
So before serving raw meat dishes to customers, it's common for restaurants to trim the meat's surface.
While Japanese law doesn't differentiate between raw and cooked beef standards, it
does distinguish between trimmed and untrimmed edges.
If followed correctly, even raw consumption shouldn't pose a high risk of infection.
After all, the Japanese have been eating this way for years without issue.
The problem was that Ebisu didn't follow the trimming process.
It's presumed that during the slaughtering process, the intestines were accidentally
ruptured, contaminating the beef with E. coli.
Ebisu's failure to trim the edges and directly serving raw beef liver sashimi to customers
led to the outbreak.
During the press conference, the president seized on this point, suggesting that if the
government truly cared for the citizens' welfare, it should ban restaurants from serving
raw beef liver.
This statement was seen by netizens as the president's shirking responsibility, especially
since two six-year-old boys had already died, increasing public dissatisfaction.
Days later, the president apologized again.
However, no apology could undo the damage.
Two more women who had dined at Ebisu passed away, along with the restaurateur's son in
October six months later.
In total, 181 people were infected and five died.
Although the president promised to support the victims, he later filed for bankruptcy
to evade compensation.
The victims collectively sued Ebisu and its president, leading to a court ordering Ebisu
to pay 169 million yen in compensation.
However, due to a lack of awareness about hemorrhagic E. coli at the time, the court
dismissed the criminal charges against the president.
Following the incident, Japanese restaurants ceased serving raw beef liver.
In October 2011, Japan officially enacted laws regarding the serving of raw meat, mandating
strict processing and health department approval for sale.
Raw beef liver sashimi was banned from July 2012 due to the discovery of hemorrhagic E.
coli not only on the surface but also inside the liver, marking the end of its availability
in Japanese restaurants.
For health's sake, it's probably for the best.