That reminds me of Buddhism's cycle of reincarnation, the six realms.
Actually, there's some distinction.
Since you brought it up, let's discuss Nietzsche's concept of eternal recurrence and Buddhism's
six realms.
The idea of eternal recurrence suggests that our lives are an endless loop.
But it's different from the six realms of Buddhism, which propose that our next life
upon death depends on whether we've done more good deeds or bad.
This determines which of the six realms we'll enter for the next cycle.
In these cycles, humans can become animals, and animals can become humans.
The six realms include the realm of gods, humans, asuras, hungry ghosts, hell, and animals.
In this cycle, humans can turn into animals and vice versa.
But eternal recurrence isn't like that.
In eternal recurrence, you are reborn as yourself, born in the same year, with the same parents,
living exactly the same life, repeating this life infinitely.
Interestingly, Nietzsche, a philosopher who knew little about mathematics and physics,
proposed a viewpoint similar to this.
It's as if, when the scientist, after much hard work, reaches the mountaintop, he finds
the philosopher already sitting there.
Nietzsche was a renowned German philosopher and poet who introduced many profound philosophical
theories.
His father passed away when Nietzsche was just five, leading behind a younger brother
and sister.
Tragically, his brother died at the tender age of two.
Nietzsche didn't shock the world or the academic community during his lifetime.
He only gained a bit of notoriety shortly before his death.
Thus, he never witnessed his own success while he was alive.
Essentially, Nietzsche was a disabled man.
His vision was nearly that of a blind person, and his body was riddled with diseases from
head to toe, leading him no comfort for work or life.
Throughout his life, Nietzsche dedicated himself to establishing new cultures and new ideas.
Even at his lowest, having contemplated suicide several times, he never placed his hope in
divine beings.
Nietzsche, often misunderstood and unable to bear prolonged solitude, eventually lost
his sanity on the streets of Turin after embracing the neck of a horse being whipped by its owner.
He died of pneumonia years later.
Nietzsche proposed an interesting question in his work related to eternal recurrence.
If you were to live your life over and over again in an endless cycle, would you want to?
That means I have to go through the coma again.
In life, there will always be suffering, sadness and unhappiness.
Some people might be experiencing these things right now.
Nobody wants to endlessly repeat these experiences because that would mean infinite suffering.
Your life can't change, so you must change your perspective.
If you view all the unpleasant parts of life as necessary experiences, then there's no issue.
Pain comes from non-acceptance.
While external factors might treat a suffering, what truly torments you is yourself.
Once you liberate your mind, you'll find happiness.
Nietzsche's life was full of suffering.
Despite his predominantly painful life, he deeply loved his fate.
He understood that in the future, many would endure similar suffering and despair.
Yet, for those brief moments of happiness in life, he felt repeating life was worthwhile.