Neither does it means going through the coma again, meeting you, makes it all worth it.
Oof, you're making me blush so much.
Finally, let's address some criticisms regarding the Pontare recurrence and its relation to our actual universe.
First off, we can't be 100% sure that any physical system state will happen again.
In addition, our universe might not meet the conditions for Pontare recurrence.
Our universe could be infinite, where energy and matter aren't concerned.
Of course, these are currently unprovable and unfalsifiable.
In summary, time being infinite leads to Pontare recurrence, and space being infinite leads to parallel universes.
The consistency of black hole physics suggests that the number of quantum states that can be accommodated in each Planck volume is finite.
This means, depending on the curvature of the universe, if the universe is closed, then every quantum state in the universe can be traversed,
indicating the inevitability of Pontare recurrence.
However, if the universe is flat or open, Pontare recurrence in the universe may not necessarily happen.
Mathematicians have proven it, that our audience might watch our video again tomorrow.